Contact

ifeomaogini@hotmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ifeomaogini-66682b71 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Home Care Critical Care Nursing Care

Ifeoma Ogini

BSN RN IV, charge Nurse, CMSRN MS Health informatics Garland, Texas

Summary

Compassionate Registered Nurse with five years' experience in healthcare. Skilled in providing exceptional care in diverse patient populations at acute medical surgical unit. Loyal and collaborative team player. Ability to establish relationships with patients/families and team members in a patient care setting. Computer skills include CareConnect (EPIC) super user, experienced in electronic health record documentations, Invisiongold, Microsoft Word, Excel, Care Fusion (Alaris pump) and Internet Navigation abilities. Strong ability to multitask, Accurately document all elements of nursing assessments, treatments, medications, discharge instructions and follow up care. Graduated my masters in health informatics. Will travel

Experience

Texas Health Resources

RN

February 2013 - Present (7 years 5 months)

Provides care to assigned patient population in accordance with the current State of Texas Nurse Practice Act, established protocols, multidisciplinary plan of care, and clinical area specific standards.

Strong ability to multitask, manage care of patients with competing priorities while fostering safe, competent and professional patient care. Demonstrated ability to assess and advocate for patient needs, develop and implement nursing care plans and maintain patient records. Clinical knowledge and proficiency in nursing and able to collaborate with interdisciplinary team for optimal delivery of patient care.

Strong assessment skills to determine necessary patient care assist patient with healing and recovery process. Provide quality nursing care in accordance with patient care policies and procedures. Educate patients on health promotion, disease management, medications, and recovery. Coordinate with doctors and other team members to develop effective care plans for patients.

Accurately document all elements of nursing assessments, treatments, medications, discharge instructions and follow up care.

Ability to establish relationships with patients/families and team members in a patient care setting. Computer skills include CareConnect (EPIC), Invisiongold, Microsoft Word, Excel, and Internet Navigation abilities.

Nurse Care Home Health Agency Dallas TX
Home Health Registered Nurse
November 2012 - December 2013 (1 year 2 months)
Dallas TX

Perform initial patient assessment. Devise and implement care plans based on individual patient assessment and analysis, assist patients in grooming, bathing and general mobility, take vitals, check blood sugar, and administer medication. Conduct patient assessments periodically. Do patient education. Write reports and provide emergency services as needed.

Texas Health Presbyterian Hospital of Dallas
Unit Secretary /Patient Care Technician in rehabilitation unit
April 2000 - November 2012 (12 years 8 months)
Dallas, TX

Provide assistance to patients according to the care plan, collect data, identify and report significant findings to nurses. Assist with patient admissions, transfers and discharges. Perform technical procedures safely and efficiently. Take actions to reduce and eliminate patients' risk. Provide basic patient care including documenting, reporting vital signs, weights, I&Os. Applying sterile and clean techniques, wound cleansing, dressing, splint application. Maintain inventory of medical supplies, clean areas and equipment. Follow standard precautions and responding to emergency situations appropriately

Education

University of South Florida

Master of Science (M.S.), Health Informatics 3.37 · (2014 - 2015)

The University of Texas at Arlington

Bachelor's degree, Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse · (2010 - 2012)

Richland Community College
Associate of Science (A.S.), Liberal Arts and Sciences/Liberal
Studies · (2008 - 2010)